Inventory of the Episcopal Church, Diocese of Wyoming, 1883-2005
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Episcopal Church. Diocese of Wyoming records
1883-2005
Episcopal Church. Diocese of Wyoming
01402
165.98 cubic ft. (194 boxes)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Collection contains correspondence, office files, publications, and photographs documenting the administration, management, activities, and work of the Episcopal Church in Wyoming.
Arrangement of the Collection
This collection is arranged in fourteen series. The first seven series are organized by Bishop in chronological order.
History of the Episcopal Church. Diocese of Wyoming.
The Episcopal Church has been in the state of Wyoming since 1856, being included in a missionary district with Colorado, Idaho, Nebraska and the Dakotas since 1859. The Missionary District of Idaho and Wyoming was created by the General Convention of October 1886. The Episcopal Church Diocese of Wyoming was established in 1896 by the Episcopal Missionary Board. By 2010, there were over 7,000 Episcopalians in Wyoming.
Bishops of the Diocese of Wyoming were: Ethelbert Talbot (1887-1896); Nathaniel S. Thomas (1909-1927); Elmer N. Schmuck (1929-1936); Winfred H. Ziegler (1936-1949); James W. Hunter (1949-1969, deceased 1987); David R. Thornberry (1969-1977, deceased 1995); Bob G. Jones (1977-1996); Bruce Caldwell (1997-2010), and John Smylie (2010-).
Scope and Content
The Episcopal Church of Wyoming collection contains the general office records of the church from 1909-2002. General office records (found in Series I through VII) largely contain correspondence documenting finances, individual churches, schools, hospitals, convocations, conventions, Board of Trustees, committees, councils, clergy, staff, and congregation. The collection also has publications, photographs, remarriage and personnel records (restriction applies), and records of the Standing Committee (restriction applies). This collection documents many aspects of the Episcopal Church in Wyoming, including the Cathedral Home for Children in Laramie, WY; Episcopal Church Women; missionary work on Wyoming Indian reservations; the Domestic and Foreign Missionary Society; and KFBU Radio Station.
Access Restrictions
Class A Restricted Records (found in Series XII, XIII, and XIV) are any records clearly identified as relating to a) Diocesan personnel, including but not limited to priests; b) remarriage files; c) the Standing Committee; d) the Commission on Ministry. Diocese hereby reserves any copyrights it possesses in and the right to control access to Class A Restricted Records which by their year date are less than seventy (70) years old. Center shall only allow access to and use of Class A Restricted Records by other persons approved in writing by Diocese. Boxes restricted under this clause: 101-118, 179; Boxes containing folders restricted under this clause: 192
Class B Restricted Records (found in Series V, VI, VII, and VIII) are defined as the class of Diocesan Office records. Diocese hereby reserves any copyrights it possesses in and the right to control access to Class B Restricted Records which by their year date are less than thirty (30) years old or until the death of the respective Bishop, whichever occurs later. Center shall only allow access to and use of Class B Restricted Records by other persons approved in writing by Diocese. Boxes restricted under this clause: 127-144, 147-150, 157, 158, 170, 193. Boxes containing folders restricted under this clause: 124-126, 146, 151, 152.
Related Materials
There are no known other archival collections created by Episcopal Church. Diocese of Wyoming at the date of processing.
Acquisition Information
This material was received from the Episcopal Church, Diocese of Wyoming in 1967 and 2008.
Access Terms
Thomas, Nathaniel S. (Nathaniel Seymour), 1867-1937; Ziegler, Winfred H. (Winfred Hamlin), b. 1885; Roberts, John, 1853-1949;; Cathedral Home for Children; Episcopal Church -- Wyoming; Episcopal Church. Missionary District of Wyoming.; Women in the Episcopal Church -- Wyoming; Episcopalians -- Wyoming; Indian reservations -- Wyoming; Missions -- Wyoming; Radio stations -- Wyoming;; Wind River Indian Reservation (Wyo.); Wyoming -- History, 1890-1918.; Wyoming -- History, 1919-1945.; Wyoming -- History, 1946-
Social Life and Customs; Religion; Missionaries; People, Ethnicity, and Culture; Wyoming
Container List
- Series I. Bishop Nathaniel S. Thomas Diocesan Office Records, 1909-1928
  Records within this series consist almost entirely of correspondence to or from Bishop Thomas covering the general administration and management of the Diocese of Wyoming.. See sub-series descriptions for more detailed information. All dates are approximate.
  - Sub-series 1. Correspondence, 1908-1927
    This sub-series contains correspondence arranged mostly alphabetically. Correspondence can also be found in sub-series 2 and 3 with the general office records. Materials in this sub-series were originally part of an earlier accretion.
    - General Correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence, 1908-1912 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - General Correspondence, 1913-1914 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - General Correspondence, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - General Correspondence, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - General Correspondence, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - General Correspondence, 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - General Correspondence, 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - General Correspondence, 1922-1923 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence, 1924-1925 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - General Correspondence, 1926-1927 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Atlantic City, Wyoming, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Basin, Wyoming, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Big Piney, Wyoming, 1915-1920 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Books, 1921-1923 (Box 31, Folder 1-2)
    - Buffalo, Wyoming, 1912-1925 (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
    - Burnt Fork, Wyoming, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Cambria, 1915 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Cambria, Wyoming, 1916-1918 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Carbon, Wyoming, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Casper, Wyoming, 1922-1925 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Cheyenne, Wyoming, 1908-1925 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Cody, 1912-1921 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Cody, Wyoming, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Dixon, Wyoming, 1920-1925 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Deaver, Wyoming, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Douglas, Wyoming, 1908-1917 (Box 4, Folder 4-6)
    - Dubois, Wyoming, 1915-1925 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Evanston, Wyoming, 1912-1925 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Fort Laramie, Wyoming, 1915-1925 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Ft. Steele, 1912 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Gillette, Wyoming, 1912-1925 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Glenrock, Wyoming, 1915-1923 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Green River, Wyoming, 1919-1923 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Greybull, 1912-1920 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Guernsey, 1914-1915 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Hanna, Wyoming, 1912-1925 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Hartville, 1912-1914 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Hudson, Wyoming, 1913 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Jackson, Wyoming, 1909-1913 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Jackson, Wyoming, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Jackson's Hole, 1914-1920 (Box 31, Folder 10-11)
    - Kemmerer, 1925 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - KFBU, 1925 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Lander, Wyoming, 1911-1921 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Laramie, Wyoming, 1912-1925 (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
    - Laramie, 1925 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Laramie, Wyoming - Archdeacon Dray, 1912-1913 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Laramie, Wyoming - Burrage, F.S., 1912-1915 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Laramie, Wyoming - Cathedral Home, 1911-1919 (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
    - Laramie, Wyoming - Cathedral Home, 1920-1925 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Laramie, Wyoming - Cathedral School for Girls, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Laramie, Wyoming - Cemetery, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Laramie, Wyoming - Deanery, 1912-1915 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Laramie, Wyoming - Ivinson Clock, 1916-1917 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Laramie, Wyoming - Jones, A.C., 1909-1913 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Lovell, Wyoming, 1921-1924 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Lusk, Wyoming, 1909-1924 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - McDermitt, 1925 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - McHenry, Donald E., 1925 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - M, 1925 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Manville, Wyoming, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Medicine Bow, Wyoming, 1914-1915 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Meeteetse, 1913-1919 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - N, 1925 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Newcastle, Wyoming, 1912-1919 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Newcastle, 1925 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - P, 1925 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Powell, 1910-1925 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - R, 1925 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Rawlins, 1912-1925 (Box 32, Folder 13-17)
    - Riverton, Wyoming, 1912-1923 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Riverton, 1925 (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Rock River, Wyoming, 1919-1920 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Rock Springs, Wyoming, 1904-1919 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Rock Springs, 1925 (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - S, 1925 (Box 32, Folder 20)
    - Saratoga, Wyoming, 1912-1921 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Savery, Wyoming, 1919 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Sheridan, 1912-1925 (Box 33, Folder 1-2)
    - Shoshoni, Wyoming, 1914-1915 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Snake River, Wyoming, 1920-1924 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Spirit of Missions, 1925 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - St. Michael's Mission, 1925 (Box 32, Folder 21)
    - Sundance, Wyoming, 1909-1919 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Sunrise, 1915 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Superior, Wyoming, 1913-1915 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Superior, 1925 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - T, 1925 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Thermopolis, Wyoming, 1912-1925 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Thermopolis, 1925 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Torrington, 1912-1925 (Box 33, Folder 8-9)
    - Voorhis, Charles B., 1925 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - W, 1925 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Wind River, 1925 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Wines, 1925 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Worland, Wyoming, 1920-1921 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Wyoming Churchman, 1925 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Sub-series 2. General Office Files, Alphabetical, 1905-1925
    Consists almost entirely of correspondence with clergy and other personnel and covering a range of topics. There is also some printed material. Materials in this sub-series were originally part of an earlier accretion.
    - Academic Reports, 1917-1918 (Box 30)
    - Akerley, Lucy D., 1925 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Annual Reports, 1915-1916 (Box 30)
    - Arapaho Village, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Archdeacon Dray, 1923 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Bishop Randall Hospital, 1905-1912 (Box 9, Folder 4-7)
    - Bishop Randall Hospital, 1913-1925 (Box 10, Folder 1-6)
    - Bishop Committees in Wyoming, 1915 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Boardman, John, 1925 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - C- Miscellaneous, 1922-1923 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Cathedral Home for Children, 1922-1923 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Certificates, 1914-1919 (Box 30)
    - Chancellor, 1914-1923 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Church Missionary Calendar, 1923 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Church Service Survey, 1923 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Circular Letters, 1923 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Clerical Possibilities, 1923 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Clericus, 1923 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Clippings, 1923 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Coe, W.R., 1923 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Confirmations, 1923 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Continental Missionary Bishops, 1923 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Contributions, 1924 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Convention, General - New Orleans, 1925 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Convocation, 1923 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Convocation- Bishop's Address, 1917 (Box 34, Folder 1-2)
    - Convocation- Bishop's Address, 1918 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Convocation- Rev. James' Address, 1917 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Convocation- Miscellany, 1917 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Corbett, Rev. A (Pinedale, Rock Springs, Eden Valley), 1912 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Corporations, 1923 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Council of Advice, 1923-1924 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Davis, Carroll M., 1923 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Diocesan, 1923-1925 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Domestic and Foreign Missionary Society, 1908-1915 (Box 11, Folder 15-17)
    - Domestic and Foreign Missionary Society, 1916-1919 (Box 12)
    - Executive Council, 1923 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Fort Laramie Project- Agreements, 1919 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Fort Laramie Project- Book List, 1918 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Fort Laramie Project- Correspondence, 1915-1921 (Box 34, Folder 8-13)
    - Fort Laramie Project- Manuscript, circa 1962 (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Fort Laramie Project- Memoranda, 1916 (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Fort Laramie Project- Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - Fort Laramie Project- Report of Harry Crain, 1916 (Box 34, Folder 17)
    - Fort Laramie Project- Report of William Dubois with Photographs, 1915 (Box 34, Folder 18)
    - Fort Laramie Project- Report of Robert Toole, undated (Box 34, Folder 19)
    - Fox Park, 1923 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Girls Friendly Society, 1923 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Greek Church- Orthodox, 1923 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Harriman, Mrs. Mary, 1925 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Healing Mission, 1923-1924 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - History- Episcopal Church in Wyoming, circa 1917 (Box 34, Folder 20)
    - Holiday House, 1923 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Home Missions Council, 1923 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Home, Robert C., 1923 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - House of Bishops, 1923 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Huntley, 1923 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Huston, Rev. Arthur, 1923 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Hutt, Robert, 1923 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Lambeth Conference, 1920 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Maps- Wyoming, undated (Box 30)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1921 (Box 30)
    - Murray, Rt. Rev. J.G., 1925 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Notes- History of Church, undated (Box 30)
    - Organ, 1925 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Parochial Reports, undated (Box 30)
    - Prayer Book, 1920-1923 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Indians, 1911-1915 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Indian's Work, 1910-1915 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Proposed Negro Episcopate, 1906-1909 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Provincial Synod, 1925 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - St. Michael's, 1918-1925 (Box 14, Folder 1-6)
    - Sermon- Lawful and Unlawful Use of Law, 1923 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Shoshones, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Thomas, Bishop- Eastern Travels, 1923 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Turner, Benjamin A., 1914-1915 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - War Memorials, 1922-1924 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Wind River Indian Mission, 1920-1921 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Wyoming - Apportionment, 1912-1918 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Wyoming- Church and Its Work, 1911-1914 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Wyoming- Church Building, 1915-1918 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Wyoming- Churchman, 1915 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Wyoming - General, 1912-1918 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Wyoming- History, 1912-1925 (Box 16, Folder 1-4)
    - Wyoming - Roll of Honor, 1918-1919 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Wyoming- Summer Workers, 1919 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Wyoming- Visitations, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Wyoming- Women Workers, 1919 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous, 1916-1917 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Sub-series 3. General Office Files, Chronological, 1909-1928
    Contains mostly correspondence with clergy and other personnel on topics such as contributions, financial transactions, convocations, staffing decisions, special projects and events, Sons of the Revolution, committees, and the general administration and management of the Diocese of Wyoming. Also includes correspondence and financial data on individual churches in Wyoming. All dates are approximate.
    - Bishop's Register, 1909-1925 (Box 59)
    - B-M, 1909-1912 (Box 39)
    - M-W, 1909-1912 (Box 40)
    - Loose Files, 1909-1916 (Box 41)
    - Church Property Records by County, 1911-1920s (Box 58)
    - Bishop Randall Hospital Board of Directors Minutes, 1911-1926 (Box 59)
    - Miscellaneous Records, 1912-1916 (Box 41-42)
    - I, P, S, 1912-1916 (Box 42)
    - A-C, 1913-1914 (Box 42)
    - C-R, 1913-1914 (Box 43)
    - S-Y, 1913-1914 (Box 44)
    - Shoshone Mercantile Company, 1914 (Box 59)
    - Miscellaneous Records, 1914-1917 (Box 44)
    - A-G, 1916-1920 (Box 44)
    - G-M, 1916-1920 (Box 45)
    - M-T, 1916-1920 (Box 46)
    - T-Z, 1916-1920 (Box 47)
    - A-U, 1919-1921 (Box 47)
    - Minutes of Wyoming Clerics, 1919-1921 (Box 59)
    - A-C, 1922 (Box 47)
    - C-S, 1922 (Box 48)
    - S-W, 1922 (Box 49)
    - A-W, 1923 (Box 49)
    - A-B, 1924 (Box 49)
    - B-J, 1924 (Box 50)
    - J-W, 1924 (Box 51)
    - B, 1925 (Box 51)
    - C-R, 1925 (Box 52)
    - S-W, 1925 (Box 53)
    - B-J, 1926 (Box 53)
    - K-T, 1926 (Box 54, 59)
    - U-Z, 1926 (Box 55)
    - A-G, 1927 (Box 55)
    - G-W, 1927 (Box 56)
    - A-W, 1928 (Box 57)
- Series II. Bishop Elmer N. Schmuck Diocesan Office Records and Personal Records, 1914-1936
  This series consists of correspondence primarily to and from Bishop Schmuck with clergy and other church personnel covering the general administration and management of the Diocese of Wyoming. Topics include finances, properties, special projects, councils, churches, Cathedral Home, Board of Trustees, and many other topics.
  - Correspondence (prior to becoming Bishop of Wyoming), 1914-1929 (Box 60)
  - Bishop Schmuck Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1929-1933 (Box 60)
  - General Office Files, 1928-1929 (Box 61)
  - General Office Files, 1930-1932 (Box 62)
  - General Office Files, 1932-1933 (Box 63)
  - General Office Files, 1933-1935 (Box 64)
  - General Office Files, 1936 (Box 65)
- Series III. Bishop Winfred H. Ziegler Diocesan Office Records, 1936-1948
  This series consists of correspondence primarily to or from Bishop Ziegler with clergy and other church personnel covering the general administration and management of the Diocese of Wyoming. Topics include, but are not limited to, finances, clergy, individual churches, Cathedral Home, National Council, publications, convocations, trustees, and Bishop Randall Hospital.
  - Records created during transition period from Schmuck to Ziegler, 1936-1937 (Box 65)
  - General Office Files, 1936 (Box 66)
  - General Office Files, 1937 (Box 66-67, 192)
  - General Office Files, 1938 (Box 67-69)
  - General Office Files, 1939 (Box 69-70)
  - General Office Files, circa 1940 (Box 71)
  - General Office Files, 1940 (Box 72-73)
  - General Office Files, 1941 (Box 73-74)
  - General Office Files, 1942 (Box 75-76)
  - General Office Files, 1943 (Box 76-78, 192)
  - General Office Files, 1944 (Box 78-79)
  - General Office Files, 1945 (Box 79-80)
  - General Office Files, 1946 (Box 80-81)
  - General Office Files, 1947 (Box 81-83)
  - General Office Files, 1948 (Box 83-84)
- Series IV. Bishop James W. Hunter Office Records, 1949-1969
  This series consists of correspondence primarily to or from Bishop Hunter with clergy and other church personnel covering the general administration and management of the Diocese of Wyoming. Topics include, but are not limited to, finances, clergy, individual churches, Cathedral Home, and National Council.
  - General Office Files, 1949-1956 (Box 84-87)
  - General Office Files, 1953-1969 (Box 121)
  - General Office Files, 1960-1969 (Box 119)
  - General Office Files, 1968-1969 (Box 120)
  - Division Reports, 1960-1968 (Box 59)
  - Churches, 1949-1959 (Box 88-90)
  - Churches, 1950-1964 (Box 122)
  - Churches, 1961-1965 (Box 123-124)
- Series V. Bishops James W. Hunter, David R. Thornberry and Bob G. Jones Diocesan Office Records, 1960-1987
  Some folders in this series are RESTRICTED, see restriction note for Class B Restricted Records (above) for details. RESTRICTED FOLDERS ARE MARKED WITH A BLACK STICKER. Restricted folders have the most recent date of material within the folder noted on them.
  This series contains a set of office files spanning the terms of three bishops. Topics include the Board of Trustees, Convention of the Diocese; Diocesan and Executive Councils; and Indian Work. Files in this series may contain correspondence, notes, plans, accounting records, speeches, and other types of materials. Also included are the reading files of Bishop Thornberry, unrestricted.
  - (Some folders RESTRICTED) General Office Files (A-B), 1960-1980 (Box 124)
  - (Some folders RESTRICTED) General Office Files (B-E), 1966-1987 (Box 125)
  - (Some folders RESTRICTED) General Office Files (D-W), 1970-1983 (Box 126)
  - Bishop Thornberry Reading Files, 1968-1975 (Box 145)
  - Bishop Thornberry Reading Files, 1976 (Box 146)
- Series VI. Bishop Bob G. Jones Office Records, 1977-1999
  RESTRICTED: As of September 2010, all materials in this series are restricted. See restriction note for Class B Restricted Records (above) for details.
  Because of the restriction, this series is not arranged in any particular order. Approximate date range given for each box so that researchers can better access some materials as the restriction is lifted. Reading files contain correspondence.
  - RESTRICTED- General Office Files, 1977-1993 (Box 127)
  - RESTRICTED- General Office Files, 1984-1993 (Box 128)
  - RESTRICTED- General Office Files, 1986-1994 (Box 129)
  - RESTRICTED- General Office Files, 1981-1996 (Box 130)
  - RESTRICTED- General Office Files, 1977-1986 (Box 131)
  - RESTRICTED- General Office Files, 1988-1991 (Box 132)
  - RESTRICTED- General Office Files, 1978-1989 (Box 133)
  - RESTRICTED- General Office Files, 1985-1995 (Box 134)
  - RESTRICTED- General Office Files, 1977-1988 (Box 135)
  - RESTRICTED- General Office Files, 1977-1993 (Box 136)
  - RESTRICTED- General Office Files, 1981-1993 (Box 137)
  - RESTRICTED- General Office Files, 1985-1987 (Box 138)
  - RESTRICTED- General Office Files, 1986-1993 (Box 139)
  - RESTRICTED- Churches in Wyoming by location, 1980-1999 (Box 140-142)
  - RESTRICTED- Bishop's Reading Files, 1978-1980 (Box 146)
  - RESTRICTED- Bishop's Reading Files, 1980-1984 (Box 147)
  - RESTRICTED- Bishop's and Others' Reading Files, 1983-1987 (Box 148)
  - RESTRICTED- Bishop's and Others' Reading Files, 1987-1989 (Box 149)
  - RESTRICTED- Bishop's and Others' Reading Files, 1990-1993 (Box 150)
- Series VII. Bishops Bob G. Jones and Bruce Caldwell Diocesan Office Records, 1984-2002
  RESTRICTED: As of September 2010, all materials in this series are restricted. See restriction note for Class B Records (above) for details.
  This series contains office files spanning the terms of Bishops Jones and Caldwell.
  - RESTRICTED- General Office Files, 1984-2002 (Box 143-144)
- Series VIII. Topics, 1898-1996
  Folders with materials dating after 1977 are RESTRICTED. See restriction note for Class B Restricted Records (above) for details. RESTRICTED FOLDERS ARE MARKED WITH A BLACK STICKER.
  This series contains material that was not originally arranged with the Bishops' General Office Files and sets of records that span across several Bishops. It includes information on groups and committees within the Church, schools and hospitals run by the Church, events, historical and informational accounts, confirmations and baptisms, and the KFBU Radio Station. Materials include registers, policies, printed information, scrapbooks, correspondence, financial records, and a variety of other materials. The Episcopal Church Women material contains audio tapes. Many of the topics in this series can also be found in the Bishops' General Office Records.
  - Annual Parochial Reports, 1973-1974 (Box 59)
  - Bishop Randall Hospital, circa 1924 (Box 59)
  - Blueprints of Churches, undated (Box 185-187)
  - Board of Trustees of Church Property minutes, 1916-1970 (Box 59)
  - Cathedral Home for Children, 1911-1943 (Box 165)
  - (some folders RESTRICTED) Cathedral Home for Children, 1941-1981 (Box 151-152)
  - Chancellor, 1941-1955 (Box 192)
  - Church Building Committee Minutes, 1939-1942 (Box 152)
  - RESTRICTED- Coalition 14 (C14), 1989 (Box 152)